<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
 <teiHeader>
   <fileDesc>
     <titleStmt>
       <title>
         Gone Girl
       </title>
       <author>
         Gillian Flynn
       </author>
     </titleStmt>
     <publicationStmt>
       <publisher>
         Crown Publishing Group
       </publisher>
        <date> 2012 </date>

     </publicationStmt>
     <sourceDesc>
       <!-- <author>Gillian Flynn
      </author> -->
       <p>
         Gone Girl was #1 on the New York Times Hardcover Fiction Bestseller list for eight weeks. It was also twenty-six weeks on National Public Radio's hardcover fiction bestseller list.[20] Culture writer Dave Itzkoff wrote that the novel was, excepting books in the Fifty Shades of Grey series, the biggest literary phenomenon of 2012. By the end of its first year in publication, Gone Girl had sold over two million copies in print and digital editions, according to the book's publisher.[19]

    Gone Girl has been widely praised in numerous publications including the New Yorker, The New York Times, Time, Publishers Weekly, Entertainment Weekly, Chatelaine, People, and USA Today. Reviewers express admiration for the novel's suspense, a plot twist involving an unreliable narrator, its psychological dimension, and its examination of a marriage that has become corrosive. Entertainment Weekly describes it as "an ingenious and viperish thriller."[16] The New Yorker describes it as a "mostly well-crafted novel," praising its depiction of an "unraveling" marriage and a "recession-hit Midwest," while finding its conclusion somewhat "outlandish."

       </p>
     </sourceDesc>
   </fileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
   <body>
     Gone Girl is a thriller novel by the writer Gillian Flynn. It was published by Crown Publishing Group in June 2012. The novel soon made the New York Times Best Seller list. The novel's suspense comes from the main character, Nick Dunne, and whether he is involved in the disappearance of his wife.

   </body>
 </text>
 </TEI>
